BAHAR HOSSEINI

FULL STACK DEVELOPER

■ bahar.hosseini@gmail.com • bahosseini.com • 548 333 3707 • Waterloo, ON in bahar-hosseini • bahar-hosseini

SUMMARY

I am a passionate full-stack developer who loves solving real-world problems using software. My background in project management has honed my ability to work efficiently in high-pressure environments while ensuring that projects are completed on time and within budget. I have a passion for writing clean and efficient code and developing user interfaces that optimize the user experience. I am committed to continuous learning and growth to stay up-to-date with the latest technologies and industry trends.

SKILLS

PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES: JavaScript, NodeJS, Ruby, TypeScript, HTML, CSS

FRAMEWORKS / LIBRARIES: React, React Native, Redux, ExpressJS, Rails, Next.js, jQuery, Saas (SCSS), Material UI, Tailwind CSS, EJS

DATABASES: PostgreSQL, SQL Server, MongoDB **TESTING:** Jest, Mocha, Chai, Storybook, Cypress

OTHERS: LINUX(Lpic1, Lpic2), Git, Github, Agile Methodology, AWS technologies (EC2, S3, Lambda, API Gateway, DynamoDB), Docker

PROJECTS

Game Station Jan. 2023 to Feb. 2023

Game Station is an e-commerce website that allows people to buy board games.

Tech stack: React, Redux Node.js, Express, MongoDB

Campr - Oct. 2022

Campr is an app inspired by AirBnB that allows people without access to camping gears to rent gears from locals with ones to spare.

Tech stack: React, Node.js, Express, PostgreSQL

jungle-rails Sept. 2022

A mini e-commerce application built with Rails 6.1 . This app allows users to add a variety of plants to their carts and order them.

Tech stack: Rails, PostgreSQL, cypress

Appointment Scheduler Sept. 2022

A React based app enabling students to book new/ edit previously booked appointments with their chosen mentor in real-time.

Tech stack: React

Test: storybook, cypress, Jest

EMPLOYMENT

Code the Change YYC [volunteer]

Software Developer · Jan. 2023 to Current · Calgary, Alberta, Canada

Tech stack: React, TypeScript, Node.js, Jest, Material UI

- Developed APIs for tracking shipping and inventory.
- Created frontend interfaces and integrated online payment processors to enhance user experience.
- Employed SheetJS to efficiently read, write, and manipulate data in spreadsheet format.
- Actively participated in code reviews, ensuring high-quality code, and collaborating with team members to identify potential improvements.

Pishro Cloud Computing

Project Manager · Mar. 2018 to July 2019

- Managed project plans using Jira, MSP, and agile methodologies to ensure successful completion of objectives and timely product delivery.
- Collaborated effectively with DevOps, Front-End, and Back-End teams, facilitating efficient workflow and timely product delivery.
- Delivered product tests with the technical team to identify software bugs, ensuring a high-quality product.
- Provided technical support to end-users during system testing, including investigating errors and launching virtual machines using Horizon (Open Stack).

Sharif ICT Innovation Center

Project Management Assistant · Aug. 2017 to Mar. 2018

- Provided comprehensive daily and periodic project progress reports to top management and stakeholders, enabling effective cross-team communication.
- Conducted rigorous quality assurance and testing to ensure the integrity and reliability of the system.
- Efficiently managed tickets and logged daily IT issues to successfully address users' issues on time.

Senobar Printing House

Project Coordinator · Oct. 2014 to July 2015

- Created Work Breakdown Structures (WBS) and effectively managed time, scope, and cost constraints to ensure successful completion of projects.
- Prepared project documents and generated comprehensive reports for stakeholders.

EDUCATION

Lighthouse Labs Oct. 2022

Diploma Lighthouse Labs Full-Stack Web Developer

Iran Azad University, Science and Research Branch 2022

Candidate for M.Sc. Industrial Engineering

Iran University of Science and Technology Sept. 2015

B.Sc. Industrial Engineering